functionofbeauty.com 2017-06-25

# Function of Beauty: Privacy Policy

##### Scope

This privacy policy explains the privacy practices for www.functionofbeauty.com. This privacy policy applies solely to information collected by this web site.

##### Data collection and use

We may use the information we collect from you when you register, make a purchase, respond to a marketing communication, visit the website, or use other site features for the following purposes: 

  * To personalize your experience and to deliver the product offerings in which you are most interested.
  * To improve our website.
  * To allow us to better respond to customer needs and service requests.
  * To determine the best method for sharing information about us or our products and services with new or existing customers.
  * To administer a contest, promotion, survey, or other site feature.
  * To process your transactions.
  * To send periodic emails regarding your account, your orders, or our products and services.
  * To respond to you regarding any reason you contacted us.

##### Your access to and control over information

Unless you ask us not to, we may contact you via email in the future. You may opt out of any future contacts from us at any time. You can do the following at any time by contacting us via email at hello@functionofbeauty.com: 

  * Unsubscribe/opt out of any future email marketing or contact.
  * Change/correct any data we have about you.
  * Have us delete any data we have about you.
  * Express any concern you have about our use of your data.

##### Registration

During registration a user is required to give certain information (such as name, physical address, email address, etc.) This information may be used to contact you about things in which we think you may be interested such as the products and/or services on our site, future products or services, and your user experience.

##### Orders

We request information from you when ordering. To buy from us, you must provide contact information (like name and shipping address), financial information (like credit card number and expiration date) and information for your desired product (profile and goals). This information is used for billing purposes, to fill your order, and for refinement and development of current and future products. If we have trouble processing an order, we'll also use this information to contact you.

##### Cookies

We use "cookies" on this site for numerous purposes. A cookie is a piece of data stored on a site visitor's hard drive to help us improve your access to our site and identify repeat visitors to our site. For instance, when we use a cookie to identify you, you would not have to log in a password more than once, thereby saving time while on our site. Cookies can also enable us to track and target the interests of our users to enhance the experience on our site. They can help us remember your preferences and offer products or services based on these preferences.

Some of our business partners may use cookies on our site (for example, advertisers). We have limited or no control over these cookies. We may also use trusted third party services that track this information on our behalf.

##### Sharing

We use outside shipping companies to ship orders and credit card processing companies to bill users for goods and services. We may also partner with other parties to provide specific services. We will share names or other contact information that is necessary for the third party to provide these services. These parties are not allowed to use personally identifiable information except for the purpose of providing these services. 

We may also release your information when we believe release is appropriate to comply with the law, enforce our site policies, or protect ours or others' rights, property, or safety.

We may share aggregated demographic information with our partners and advertisers. Non-personally identifiable visitor information may also be provided to other parties for marketing, advertising, or other uses.

##### Security

We take precautions to protect your information. No online transmission or transaction is 100% secure. However, when you submit sensitive information via the website, your information is protected.

Wherever we collect sensitive information (such as credit card data), that information is encrypted and transmitted to us in a secure way. You can verify this by looking for a closed lock icon in your web browser, or looking for "https" at the beginning of the address of the web page.

While we use encryption to protect sensitive information transmitted online, we also protect your information offline. Only employees who need the information to perform a specific job (for example, billing or customer service) are granted access to personally identifiable information.

##### Links

This web site contains links to other sites. Please be aware that we are not responsible for the content or privacy practices of other sites. We encourage our users to be aware when they leave our site and to read the privacy statements of any other site that collects personally identifiable information.

##### Surveys

From time-to-time our site may request information via surveys. Participation in these surveys is completely voluntary and you may choose whether or not to participate and therefore disclose this information. Information requested may include contact information (such as name and shipping address), demographic information (such as zip code, age level), and product preferences. Survey information will be used for purposes of monitoring or improving the use and satisfaction of this site and our products or services.

##### Children’s privacy

We do not knowingly collect personally identifiable information from children under 13. If you are a parent or guardian and you learn that your children have provided us with personal information, please contact us immediately at hello@functionofbeauty.com. If we become aware that we have collected personal information from a children under age 13 without parental consent, we will take steps to remove that information from our servers.

##### Do not track disclosure

We do not support Do Not Track (“DNT”). Do Not Track is a preference you can set in your web browser to inform websites that you do not want to be tracked. Our site does not currently support this preference.

##### Effective date and policy updates

This privacy policy is effective as of January 20, 2016. Our privacy policy may change from time-to-time and revised policies will be posted on this page.

If you have any questions about this privacy policy or how we use your data, please contact us immediately via email at hello@functionofbeauty.com.
